Never forget why you are the church.
Um, So,
Typically
would be in Romans, um,
Chapter 12.
And that's uh, that's my comfort zone
because we've been in Romans for the last 7.5 years.
So I just kind of know what's going
on in Romans.
As a matter of fact, the running joke.
We had a young man, his name's Elijah Burns, 23 years old.
I'm no longer the youngest pastor, lead pastor in the
association, by the way, that's been beaten.
But as I go on, it's going to continue to get beaten, but or hopefully it does.
Amen?
And he started Romans like 3 months ago.
A little rookie and uh, He's like in chapter 11.
I'm like, brother, are you reading scripture and dismissing or are you like preaching the word?
So anyway, the running joke is, you know, that
I take too long in preaching the
word, but we were going to go over Romans 12, verse 9, and
uh, Then, um,
yesterday I was mowing the yard at my parents' house,
by the way, was it not hot yesterday?
I'm talking like significantly, huh?
By the way, who helped with the auction?
Raise your hand if you help it, give them a hand because, uh,
The auction, that's that's how we fundraise for our students.
And so, um, you know, that's that's a big deal led my brother Wesley.
So, um, I'm sure that was not enjoyable.
But I don't know if you know or not.
But we have a a, um, a resource
to you on, uh, you
can listen to the set list and the worship songs that we're going
to be singing throughout this month.
So we have a June set list, and then
all the songs that we're going to do each week are on that set list.
So a lot of times if you don't know the songs, a lot of
people, maybe newer songs, older songs, whatever, but
you can you can go there and you can anywhere music is played,
you can find not anywhere, but those 3 places that music are played,
you can find the music.
And so I was doing that, right?
I don't want to be a pastor that tells you to do something that I don't do.
And so I was worshiping and I
don't know about you, but man, the best time to worship is on the lawnmower because
you can just scream as loud as you want and really, you don't think anyone
hears you, but you know they kind of do.
So like when me was singing, I do things that are risky and know that
it probably didn't come out right, but hey, who cares?
I'm in the lawnmower.
And I was just, I was just going, it was going through the set list.
And I'm trying to get to this place.
I'm telling you, when I get off course, I get all uncomfortable, so we're just going to have to do what we do this morning.
Um, and same God came up.
And I
just put that thing on repeat.
I mean, on repeat.
And Mike, you basically, in a sentence, preach
my message when you talk before the song, so, you know, forget you,
bro, but anyway, um, But
I just got to thinking about it.
And There
was so much going on yesterday.
We set out the chairs and and that was a big
change and it was funny because one of my brothers,
he came in and he was like, man, it looks so great.
He said, man, you did it.
I said, man, I didn't do all I did was just pick out what kind of chair.
And I knew what he meant, though, because this has been something we prayed about for so long.
And I
just got a thinking about how, man, there's so much change.
in life.
is changing in a church setting.
We have people that are no longer with us that are in heaven.
We have people that are no longer with us,
but with another local church doing and serving the Lord there.
I mean, if I think about all the faces that I've seen,
all the things that we've done, it's we were setting the chairs out yesterday and the
guys that were here with us, we worked out, Taylor,
Wangard, he, if you see him, he's the rip guy with the big beard, looks like a Viking.
He was the one that was leading the workout, but he
came hurt so he didn't do the workout.
You know what I'm saying?
But either way, and he put us through it.
Like I almost threw up.
But anyway, but as we were saying, man, isn't it
awesome to, you know, you don't think about this, but one day we're
going to be able to say, hey, man, I remember when we put the chairs in, the worship center,
and it was such a big deal, just a little thing of chairs.
And then even in my own personal life, we're
going from 2 children to 3 children and we've
been doing a renovation on the bonus room and and,
you know, they've been sleeping.
We got the beds up and all the wall decor, you know, because they're girls,
so it's not just how you go sleep.
It's like they need flowers and all the things because you want girls to grow
up, you know, girly, you know what I'm saying, in a world that doesn't like it.
So, you know, we're sitting there and we're just thinking, man, it looks
so different and it's just a lot of change going on and I
know it's not just my life, but it's your life as well.
So I got to thinking about that and connecting it with everything.
And listen, I don't believe it's a bad thing to be sentimental.
I believe God has created us with emotions.
I believe God created us to want
and desire to be able to look back and remember
what he's done and be able to see what he's doing now and
to be able to have the faith, to believe that he's going to do it again,
even if it doesn't look the same as it did before.
And so he made us relational.
We easily attach ourselves to things.
That's why it's so important to make
sure that we're clinging to Christ because if we don't, we will attach
our things, attach ourselves to the things of
the world, but again, although much changes over
the years, I want you to know, God remains the same.
Now, if you're a guest today, understand something.
We will be in Romans and going word by word.
We don't do verse by verse here.
We do word by word.
And so we'll be back in what we do on a regular basis
next week, but if you would just turn your Bibles to Hebrews chapter 13.
Hebrews chapter 13.
If you remember me saying, man, I know what's odd.
Just stick with me.
We'll get out of here in a little bit.
Maybe, I don't know.
Sometimes I talk more when I don't have a script.
Y'all just got scared.
Hebrews chapter 13.
We see this concept
of God never changing and remaining the same
throughout all scriptures.
So we're in Hebrews 13, but Psalm 102, 27,
but thou art the same, and thy years shall
have no end.
Malachi chapter 3, verse 6,
for I am the Lord, I change not.
And that says, therefore, because that he
changes not, ye sons of Jacob are not consumed,
because he is faithful, we are not consumed.
James 117,
every good thing, give every good thing given, and every perfect
gift is from above, coming down from the
Father of lights, which whom there is no variation or shifting shadow.
In other words, God never changes.
And then we get to Hebrews 13, verse 8.
It says, Jesus Christ is the same yesterday.
And today, and forever.
And so in this time of change.
Whatever that looks like for you.
Whether it's good change or bad change.
My purpose this
morning is to encourage you.
Let's pray, Father, I Thank you, Lord, for your word.
I thank you.
Just for your guidance.
even though sometimes I don't
feel like I'm being guided as specific as what I'd like.
So God, I pray that as you have spoken to me,
God, you speak through me.
And I pray those that have
ears to hear, may they hear.
And I pray we can leave out of
here, God trusting you more.
In Jesus' name we pray.
Amen.
Some
want to expire the Bible's relevancy today, and they really
what they want to do is they want to separate who God
was from who he is today.
As a matter of fact, I was talking not too long ago
with somebody and they say, well, how can the God of the Old Testament be
the God of the New Testament?
And listen, I don't have time to preach you all the nuances of that,
but because the word says so.
And so you might say, well, well,
what does that even mean?
And who cares about that or whatever it is?
Listen, church, it is not possible for God to change.
As a matter of fact, we see in his word, Isaiah chapter 40,
verse 8, the grass withers, the flower fades,
but the word of our God stands forever.
I want to stay forever, forever.
That's forever.
It's kind of like all the smart preachers
that say, hey, you don't know Greek, but let me teach you a Greek lesson.
All in Greek means all, right?
Forever just simply means forever.
His word endures forever.
See, we serve a God who never changes.
His character is eternal.
His love is enduring.
His mercy is flowing, his grace is
sufficient, and his plan is final.
That's the God we serve.
But sometimes, see, what happens is in
all the change that we experience.
We forget this.
We forget that God...
is the same.
We forget the constant character of
God through it all.
So we come to Hebrews 13.
Verse 8, it says this, Jesus Christ.
is the same yesterday.
And today, and forever.
Now, the author of Hebrews
gives us a threefold truth of the immutability of God.
So in other words, God is immutable.
That's a big word, you may not have ever heard it or don't really care to know what it means.
All that means is that he does not change.
That's what we're explaining here today.
The immubility of God is, is that he does not change.
There's 3 things about that.
He is the same yesterday.
He is the same today, and he is the same for the rest of our tomorrows.
As a matter of fact, I don't know what God is going
to do tomorrow, the good thing is this.
I know that he's already there.
So I can trust him, no matter what is
gonna happen, that he is going to have a plan for my life.
So what does that mean for us?
Well, if we look to scriptures for the examples of this?
We get a lot of examples about how God
does not change and even though we change in our life
and even those circumstances are, you know, change and
situations do, God remains the same.
I think about the same God who walked and talked with Adam
and Eve in the garden is the same God who blessed
them with another son after Cain murdered Abel.
We think, man, how could they have focused on all because God did not change.
The same God who had Moses walking
through on dry land, the Red Sea is the
same God, even though he wandered through the wilderness for 40 years.
God did not change, even though the circumstance changed.
The same God who called David to go
and slay Goliath, just like we sang about with a sling
and a stone, is the same God who was with them
in the cave running for his life from King Saul.
God did not change, even though the circumstance did.
The same God who called Abraham in his old age.
to follow him and to trust him is
the same God who called the disciples as teenagers.
It's the same God.
The same God who, when
Peter, in his rejection of Christ, went away
grieved, was the same God, who had Peter stand up
and preach the gospel, and that they had Pentecost,
and see 3000 saved that day.
He's the same God.
The same God.
When Paul, he was the one living and persecuting
Christians and persecuting the church, the same God who
knew him then, the same God was the one who saved
him, and now Paul gave his life for that same God.
The same God
who labels in his in scripture that the apostle
John was the beloved disciple and how he
was the one who took care of the mother of Jesus,
was the same God who called him into exile,
Patmos, where he had the vision for revelation, the
same God, no matter the situation.
He's the same God.
Now I know what you're thinking.
That sounds really cool.
And just like Mike said, like we separate
scripture from our lives too often.
We separate the fact that,
yes, it's been 1000s of years, but the
same God they served even back then all the way
in Genesis is the same God that we're
serving right here and right now.
And I pray that it's the same God that you and I'll be.
I know me.
I pray for you that will be serving for the rest of eternity.
But I want to encourage you today.
I'm going to be honest with you.
I't have much to say outside of encouragement today.
don't know.
I don't know who needs to hear it.
I don't know what God is going to do.
I'm not trying to put him in a box.
He's he's God.
Amen.
He can do what he wants.
But how does that hit you today?
Well, the same God who delivered you from that addiction.
can deliver you today.
The
same God who you stood before and promised, To
your spouse for better or for worse is the same God, even though it seems more for worse.
And for better.
The same
God who gave you that baby is the same God who is holding you as you grieve the loss.
of that baby.
The same God who
is with you when you were healthy is the same God who is going
to walk with you through that diagnosis.
He's the same God.
The
same God you dedicated your children to is the same God who cares for them,
even though they're running away from him.
The
same God who is with you when you had much is the same God who is with you
when you have little.
Church,
it was awesome when I was baptizing cannon.
You know,
and he was nervous and and I was just talking and
trying to make them feel better and, you know, because we're about to get in the water.
once we're in the water, it's as good as done.
You know what I'm saying?
Like there ain't no getting out of the water unless you dunked, you know?
That's why I work out.
Like, you're not getting out.
You know what I'm saying?
I'm going to grab onto you and you're going to go underwater.
But I was just trying to make them feel better.
And I sat down in front.
I said, man, I said, listen, I said, dude, I have done this like over a 100 times.
He's like, what?
The same God that I
was serving 10 years ago as pastor.
It's the same God that I'm serving today.
Listen,
we go through shifts and we go through stages and we
go through phases in our life and there's story after
story and life after life in this church right here, right now.
Where if you look at your if
you just look back 5 years, 10 years, 20
years, whatever it is, however, you're thinking, man, I could
never have imagined God would have me right here, right now.
You
know, we were, uh, it was Michael was talking and
and Michael, he definitely, I don't know if you do or not.
Maybe you just know every single song that's ever been written for the Lord, but he
usually sits right over there during rehearsal before life groups,
and man, you can just see him over there just singing while they're singing.
And it was awesome because he came up to me.
He said, man, he said, how did we get so lucky as
to get a worship team like this?
And my answer was, I don't know.
But what I'm trying to say is, listen, hey,
we sit here and we think, man, it's awesome, and they got
every everyone that stands on the stage has everything together.
Listen, if you ask Mike and Robin their testimony, they'll tell you 2
years ago, their life didn't look the same as it does now.
But yet God is the same.
He's the same God.
See,
we have mountaintop experiences and we have times in the valley.
But he's the same God.
I just want to remind you.
Again, Jesus Christ is the same yesterday
and today and forever.
And if we look at the song that we sang, It
says you heard your children then, you hear your children now.
Guys, I'm a child of God.
You are the same God.
You answered prayers back then and you will answer now.
Let me ask you something.
Has God answered prayers in your life?
Then why do we doubt that he'll answer today?
You
are providing then you are providing now.
Has God provided for you in your life?
Then why do we doubt he's going to provide today?
I just want to be transparent with you.
That's one I struggle with.
I grew up with the mindset of you
provide, you provide, and you provide the best way possible.
And so any little shift in that provision,
I start to get all nervous and antsy, but listen, hey, you know what that is?
That's a lack of trust in the God who's provided for me
my whole life.
You
move them power then, God move in power now.
He's the same God.
Guys,
I can remember where there was times in this church.
Where after the gospel was preached, man, people were so moved.
You couldn't find a, you couldn't find a spot.
You do realize this church didn't always have tissue boxes under the chairs.
But what happened is God began to move and break us,
so we had to find something to wipe our tears off of our face.
So we had to buy tissues.
Listen, God moved in a mighty powerful way then.
He can do that again now.
He's the same God.
You were a healer then.
you are a healer now.
He's the same God.
How many people that we have in our congregation right now who are sick.
But
the same God who had you when you were healthy.
He has you right now.
You are a savior then, you are a savior now.
I love how I,
when we talk about salvation.
Listen, I'm saved yesterday, today.
And I'm saved tomorrow.
And if tomorrow comes, I'm saved tomorrow again.
I'm saved forever.
And it says this, 0 God, my God, I need you.
Oh God, my God, I need you now.
Oh, Rocko Rock of
Ages, I'm standing on your faithfulness.
But then it says this, and we didn't
sing this part, and that's okay, but it says, you freed the captives then.
You are freeing hearts right now.
I wonder if there's anyone here this morning who's bound up in their heart.
Whether it be doubt or
discouragement or resentment or bitterness or unforgiveness
or or anger or lust.
What are you bound up in in your heart?
You touch the lepers then, I feel your touch.
right now.
And then it says, I'm calling
on the Holy Spirit, almighty river, come and feel me.
Again.
The
Bible is full of people who at times in their life did not know what to do.
Have you ever been there, church?
Have you ever been in a place to where you just simply didn't know what to do?
Where to turn or how to go?
You might be there right now.
And
in those times, those people they had a decision to make.
Every single account in God's word.
There was always times and multiple times in their life where
they could have gone one way or the other, but there was only 2 ways.
Either trust God or don't.
And what we see is,
even though God's grace is sufficient, even though God is merciful to us and
his mercy is new every day, those who decided to not trust God,
man, that path took them to destruction.
But those who decided to trust God,
even though destruction seemed near God delivered them.
Our
decision this morning is no different.
Are you going to trust God?
Or are you not?
You
might be in a situation you never thought you'd be in.
Are you gonna trust God?
Or are you not?
You
might be in a situation you never thought could happen to you.
Are you going to serve
him in your doubt and discouragement?
Are you going to decide to not trust them?
I think of, and I don't, I don't, this is why I need a script.
But I think of, um,
you know, my daddy's standing, he's sitting right here.
Really, you're in my seat, but that's okay.
You can sit there.
Because, you know, we do that here.
But I think about changes and
I wasn't even thinking about this when I thought about this, but I'm looking at him now and he,
listen, things happened in his life here recently.
He never thought would happen.
But the same
God who had you then has you now.
As a matter of fact, there was a there
was a moment we didn't know if we'd still have them here.
But God is faithful.
And guess what?
He may feel weak, he may feel broken still.
But God's not weak.
And God's not broken.